Guys, we've got trouble!
（鶫）大変よ　みんな！！
（アルゴ）どうした？
What's wrong?
The Leukocyte was just fired at Point Delta!
ルーカサイトが　今
ポイントデルタに発射されたわ！
（綾瀬）涯のいる場所に？
At where Gai is?
The Leukocyte is a constellation
of Quasi-Zenith Satellites.
（四分儀）ルーカサイトは
準天頂衛星で構成される→
衛星コンステレーションです。→
When it's completed, it will have
full 24-hour coverage directly over Japan
完成すれば　２４時間
死角なく　常に　日本上空から→
and be able to strike literally
any target in our country at any time.
任意の目標を撃てるようになる。
Why build something like that?
（集）どうして　そんなものを…。
To exterminate the Japanese people.
（涯）「日本人を抹殺するためだ」
Gai?!
（鶫）涯！？
（綾瀬）無事ですか？　ケガは！？
Are you all right? Are you injured?
They're just scratches.
（涯）「かすり傷だ」
And Kyo and the others?
（アルゴ）キョウたちは？
They were unlucky.
（涯）「運がなかった」
（どよめき）
（涯）増援も全滅。
補給物資も回収不能だ。
All our reinforcements were annihilated,
and the supplies are unrecoverable.
[無線]（四分儀）いったん
立て直しますか？
Shall we take a moment to regroup?
No. There's no time to waste now.
（涯）いや。
もはや　一刻の猶予もない。
（涯）行動を開始する。
We'll begin our operation.
So, everything that makes me whole
♪♪～
I'll now give to you
I'm yours
Say, there's lots of happiness
in this world, isn't there?
Someday, if we're together
Even if someone calls you a liar
And tries to hurt you with heartless words
Even if the world tries to make
you wear a crown of thorns
Without even trying to believe in you
I can take your side, and yours alone
I know that solitude, that pain
So, everything that makes me whole
I'll now give to you
cage
（四分儀）涯。　よろしいですか？
（涯）ああ。
Are you ready, Gai?
Yes.
（涯）揃ったようだな。
It looks like we're all here.
The target of this operation is
the Leukocyte control facility
今回の作戦目標は
月ヶ瀬ダムの底。
ルーカサイトの
コントロール施設だ。
at the base of the Tsukigase Dam.
俺たちは　その最深部へ潜入し
コントロールコアを停止させる。
We're going to sneak into its
bottom floor and stop the control cores.
ぶっ壊すんすか？
Are we gonna smash 'em up?
研二。
Kenji.
（城戸）はいよ。→
Yessir.
これがルーカサイト。→
This is the Leukocyte.
地上からの量子暗号システムで
コントロールされてるってわけだ。
See, it's controlled through a quantum
cryptography system on the ground.
And 200 meters below
the dam... da-dum!
（城戸）で　ダムの地下２００ｍに
ドーン！→
これが　そのコントロール装置。→
This is the control device.
コアは　超伝導のフロートケージに格納されてて→
The cores are housed in
a superconductive "float cage,"
and it switches to "autistic mode"
in response to any physical stimulus.
物理刺激を受けると
自閉モードに切り替わる。→
At that point it's game over.
こうなったら　もう　お手上げさ。→
外部からの操作を
一切　受け付けなくなるんだ。
You won't be able to manipulate
it from the outside at all.
In other words, in order to send
this thing the signal to stop,
（城戸）
つまり　停止信号を送るには→
you have to manipulate the control
cores without touching them.
コントロールコアを
触れずに操作するしかない。
（ざわめき）
（アルゴ）触れずに？
Without touching them?
そこに　集と研二の役割がある。
あっ。
That's where Shu and Kenji come in.
Their abilities, the King's Right Hand
and the gravity-controlling Void,
２人の能力。
王の右手と　重力制御のヴォイド。
are the keys to this operation.
それが　この作戦の鍵だ。
However, with our reinforcements wiped out...
しかし　増援が
断たれたことについては…。
I have a new proposed plan here.
ここに　新たな作戦案がある。
Our projected casualties are up
from 5% to 35%, but it's doable.
こちらの損害予測が
５％から３５％になったが→
実行は可能だ。
各人　共有頼む。
それは→
I'm asking you all to share this.
Are you saying one out of three of us will die?
３人に１人は　やられるってこと？そんなの…。
That's...
いずれ
危険は　この国全体に広がる。
The danger will spread to this whole country soon.
We have no choice but to contain it now.
俺たちが食い止める他ない。
やだよ　そんなん。
I don't like it.
If someone dies because I screw up,
they'll have died for nothing, won't they?
僕が失敗して　誰か死んだら
犬死にってことでしょ。
I'll bear the responsibility.
責任は　俺が負う。
キョウたちの責任も？
For Kyo and the others, too?
言うだけなら簡単だよ。
Words are cheap.
僕は　参加を辞退します。
（ざわめき）
I'm pulling out of this one.
Hey, Shu.
（アルゴ）おい　集！
好き勝手　さえずってんじゃねえぞ！
Stop talking like a spoiled brat.
I'm saying this for your sake.
みんなのために言ってるんです。
あの人についていくのは
おかしいって！
It's just messed up to follow him!
You little...
（アルゴ）てめえ！
（城戸）ちょっと　ちょっと！
Hold on, hold on.
Who's being a pain here, you or Gai?
Read the social cues, okay?
今　この場で厄介なのは
君と涯　どっち？
（城戸）空気　読もうよ。
（アルゴ）だってよ。
You heard the man.
（失笑）
What now?
どうします？
ああ…。
Right...
作戦の変更は　なしだ。
以上！
There'll be no change of plans. Dismissed!
Shu.
（いのり）集。
いのりさんですか…。
Oh, good afternoon, Inori.
すみませんね
迷惑掛けちゃって。
I apologize for causing you trouble.
でも　皆さんだって→
But they don't listen to me eith...
僕の言うこと…。
（いのり）その感じ嫌。　やめて。
Stop talking like that. I hate it.
ごめん。
Sorry.
（いのり）集。
Shu.
（いのり）私の言うとおりにして。
Do exactly as I say.
≪（雷鳴）
Leukocyte 3 will transition into
its planned orbit in another four hours,
（茎道）「あと４時間で
ルーカサイトスリーは　予定軌道に遷移し→
おりが完成する。
それまでは待機だ」
and the cage will be complete.
You're on standby until then.
I regret to say it won't be in time, then.
（嘘界）では　残念ながら
間に合いませんね。→
Funeral Parlor's attack will come
in two hours, seventeen minutes.
葬儀社の攻撃は２時間１７分後です。
（茎道）「独自の情報源かね？」
（嘘界）いえ。
Do you have a private source of information?
No, it's simply a gut feeling...
or perhaps it's more of a hope.
（嘘界）ただの勘…。
というより　希望ですかね。
This is one time I hope
your instincts are off, Segai.
（茎道）「今回ばかりは　君の読みが
外れることを願うよ　嘘界君」
（ローワン）２時間１７分後？
Two hours and seventeen minutes?
（ダリル）日没の時間では？
Sounds like sundown.
O-Oh, I see. They'll come at sundown!
（ローワン）そうか。
やつらは日没に来る。
（ローワン）退院後初の復帰戦になるが
大丈夫か？
This will be your first battle
since coming out of the hospital.
Will you be all right?
Excuse me?!
（ダリル）あぁ！？
誰に向かって言ってるのさ！
Who do you think you're talking to?
（ローワン）あっ！→
あーあ。
あの　くそ虫どもが
僕のシュタイナーを…。
Those little maggots took my Steiner...
I'll never forgive them.
絶対　許さない！
Even if they come to me crying and
apologizing, I'll still pull the trigger.
やつらが　泣いて謝っても
僕は　撃つのをやめない。
Hmm? Did you say something, Lieutenant?
えっ　何か言ったか？　少尉。
（嘘界）《さあ　早く来て
君の選択を見せてください》→
Come, hurry here and show me your choice.
《こんな気持ち→
This feels almost like falling in love
for the first time, Shu Ouma!
まるで初恋のようですよ。
桜満　集君》
♪♪～
≪（ハッチの開く音）
久しぶりに　こたえた。
Nothing's gotten to me like that in a while.
いったい　何のために
こんなことをしているのか…。
What the hell am I doing all this for?
If you want the truth, it was all
I could do to keep up my "leader" face.
正直
リーダーの顔をしているだけで→
手いっぱいだった。
ルーカサイトからの攻撃の直後→
Right after the Leukocyte attack, Kyo was still alive.
キョウは　まだ生きていた。
（爆発音）
（キョウ）《ハァ…　ハァ…》→
《うっ…。　涯さん…。
ありがとうございます》→
Gai... Thank you so much.
《僕の声が　いいって
言ってくれたこと→
I'll remember my whole life...
that you told me you liked my voice...
一生　忘れません》→
《一生…》
My whole life...
（キョウ）《涯さん…》
Gai...
（銃声）
笑っていたよ。
She was smiling.
She was glad I was fine...
glad that she was the one to die.
俺が無事でよかった。
死ぬのが自分でよかったと。
だから　問い掛けていたのさ。
So I started to ask myself...
"Is Gai Tsutsugami someone
who can repay their sacrifice?"
恙神　涯という人間は
彼らに報いる存在なのか。
こんな俺でいいのか？　と。
"Shouldn't I be better than this?"
あ…。
俺は　みんなに信じさせているよりずっと　ちゃちな人間なんだ。
I'm a much smaller man than I let them all believe.
Really I'm nothing... I should be
the very first one selected out...
本来なら　真っ先に
淘汰されてしまうような→
ちっぽけな…。
≪（カーテンの開く音）
盗み聞きか。
Eavesdropping, eh?
いい趣味だな。
うっ…。
You have such nice hobbies.
聞きたくなかったよ。
そんな涯は見たくなかった。
I didn't want to hear that.
I didn't want to see that side of you, Gai.
俺を　どういう男と思っていた。
What kind of guy did you think I was?
もう分かったろ！
You get it now, don't you?
I lose confidence and get upset,
and I let other people spoil me.
俺は　自信なく　うろたえ
人に甘える。
Inori, too?
いのりにも…。
That's right.
そうさ。
ぐあっ！
うああぁ！！
みんなの命を背負って→
Do you think I can shoulder everyone's
lives and not feel any of the weight?
何の重みも感じずに
いられると思うか。
俺は　鈍感でありたくない。
I don't want to be indifferent.
みんなの気持ちに応えたい。
I want to be worthy of everyone's feelings.
うっ…。
手伝うよ　僕も。
I'll help, too.
バカなやつだ。
You're a fool.
It's time.
[無線]（四分儀）時間です。
Begin the operation.
作戦開始。
Black Swan to all units. Open combat!
[無線]（鶫）ブラックスワンより
全ユニット　コンバット　オープン！
≪（アラーム）
（兵士）敵襲！
Enemy attack!
Is it Funeral Parlor?
（兵士）葬儀社か？
（兵士たち）うおっ！
Major Segai!
（ローワン）嘘界少佐！
エンドレイヴを出してください。
Send out the Endlave, please.
♪♪～
（ダリル）「あぁ　これだよ　これ！
これこそ　僕だ。　ダリル・ヤンだ！」
This is it! Yes! This is what Daryl Yan is about!
（綾瀬）「あんたの子
乗り心地　いいわよ」
Your baby here is a sweet ride!
（ダリル）「シュタイナー。
僕の…！」→
Steiner... My Steiner...
Give it back! Give it back, give it back!
「返せ　返せ　返せ　返せっ！！」
Give it back!
Thanks, Oogumo!
（綾瀬）「サンキュー　大雲！」
Gai, the diversion's coming off
pretty well. Are you in yet?
[無線]（鶫）涯。　陽動は　おおむね成功。
もう　入れた？
Yeah. I'm going to turn off
my communicator for a while.
「ああ。　しばらく　通信を切る。
祈っていてくれ」
Pray for us.
Come back soon.
早く帰ってきてね。
「ああ」
Right.
走れ！
Run!
You haven't fired a single round, Shu Ouma.
（城戸）全然　撃ってないね。
桜満　集君。
It's all I can do to keep running!
走るのに精いっぱいなんだ。
（城戸）早く慣れなよ。
Hurry up and get used to killing people already.
人殺しに。
そーれ！→
Aaaand... boom!
ドーン！
The cores are in here. Let's go.
コアは　この奥だ。
行くぞ。
（兵士）うわっ！
どんどん来る！
ここは私が。
They just keep coming!
I'll take care of things here.
いい？　涯。
Okay, Gai?
好きにしろ。
Suit yourself.
ありがとう。
えっ…。　えっ？
Thank you.
H-Huh?
≪（銃声）
（兵士）うわっ！
I don't want to kill you if I can avoid it.
できれば　殺したくない。
だから　来ないで。
So stay back.
Damn it!
（兵士）くそっ！
（兵士）うおおっ！
バカな人たち。
Fools.
≪（銃声）
（兵士たち）うああ！
I-Inori?! Why?
いのり！？　何で…。
Come on, quit dawdling.
（城戸）ほら！
ぐずぐずしてないでさ→
Hurry up and take it.
早いとこ取っちゃってよ。
出番でしょ？
俺のヴォイドの。
It's time for my Void, right?
コアルームに　何者かが侵入！
Someone's invaded the core room!
（嘘界）スワップの準備を。
Prepare to swap.
♪♪～
（ダリル）「世話が焼けるなぁ
まったく！」
Sheesh, you're so high-maintenance.
さてと。
お迎えの時間ですかね。
Now, then. I believe it's time to go fetch him.
The center?
真ん中？
そうだ。　慎重にいけ。
Yes. Be careful.
When they've stopped circuiting,
Funell will input the stop command.
回転が止まったら
ふゅーねるが停止信号を書き込む。
んっ！
あっ！
（ダリル）「ハロー！
会いたかったよ。　恙神　涯」→
Hello! I've been wanting
to see you, Gai Tsutsugami.
「僕を　こけにした報い
存分に受けてもらおうか」
I'll pay you back real good for making a fool of me.
涯！
お前は集中しろ！
Gai!
You just concentrate!
（ダリル）「うおお！！」
ダリル！
そこにはコアがあるんだ！→
Daryl, the cores are in there!
Don't overdo it!
やり過ぎるな！！
ふっ！
Shu!
集！
くっ…！
（ダリル）「何だ？」
What?
You piece of shit!
（ダリル）「このっ！　くそがぁ！」
すごい…！
≪（物音）
Wow...
あっ！　涯！
Gai!
（颯太）頑張れ！
トク…。→
Hang in there, Toku...
"No signal. Please check your
antenna's settings and tuning."
あれ？
Huh?
[TEL]（不通音）
[無線]（鶫）大変よ！　涯！
「どうした？」
Bad news, Gai!
What is it?
（鶫）ルーカサイトワンの
様子が　おかしいの！
Something's wrong with Leukocyte 1
（ローワン）コアの破損で
姿勢制御が誤作動！→
Damage to the core is making
the attitude control malfunction!
It's falling out of orbit!
軌道を下げてます！
[無線]（鶫）このままだと　ルーカサイトワンは
質量のほとんどを保持したまま→
At this rate, Leukocyte 1 will crash
in Tokyo with most of its mass intact!
東京に落ちるわ！
♪♪～
Shu. Give me the pen.
集。　ペンを出せ。
えっ？
お前が
ＧＨＱに持たされたペンだ。
The pen GHQ made you take. Give it to me.
あれを出せ。
あっ。
So you were on to me, then.
≪（嘘界）気付かれていましたか。→
It seems you got by without pushing it, eh, Ouma?
どうやら　押さずに
済んだようですね。　桜満君。
That's a bit of a shame,
but at the moment I'm glad.
少し残念ですが　今は　ありがたい。
貴様が嘘界か。
You're Segai?
（嘘界）初めまして。　恙神　涯君。
I'm pleased to meet you, Gai Tsutsugami.
取引だ。
これで衛星を何とかしてやる。
I'll make you a deal. I'll use this
to do something about the satellite.
その代わり　一連の事件で得た
桜満　集に関するデータを→
In exchange, you erase all the data on Shu Ouma
that you've gathered from these incidents.
全て抹消しろ。
フフッ！
The signal from your pen is
connected to the Leukocyte.
お前のペンのシグナルは→
ルーカサイトに
つながっていたんだ。
The Leukocyte was programmed to fire
at it when you pushed the buttons.
ボタンを押したら
そのペンを標的に→
発射されるようになっていた。
Which means if we get the firing
satellite, the falling satellite,
だから
撃つ衛星と　落下する衛星→
そして　標的となる　このペンを
一直線につなげば→
and this pen all lined up,
衛星を撃ち落とせるはずだ。
we should be able to shoot it down.
でも　それって　誰かが自分を
的にするってことじゃないか！
But... doesn't that mean someone
would be making himself the target?!
（アルゴ）涯が出てるって！？
Gai's outside?! What's going on?!
どういうことだ？
（綾瀬）「分からないわ！
とにかく　今は援護よ！」
I don't know.
But right now we need to cover him!
《また　見てるだけか…》
Just gonna stand back and watch again?
《いいのか？　桜満　集！》
Are you okay with that, Shu Ouma?
Do you want to save them, Shu?
「救いたい？　集」
いのり？
Inori?
「集…。　救いたい？」
Shu... do you want to save everyone? Save Gai?
「みんなを。　涯を」
うん。
Yeah.
「聞いたよ？」
I heard that.
♪♪～
《勝負だ》
The fight is on. Will I be the one selected out,
《淘汰されるのは　俺の方か
あるいは　世界か》
or will it be the world?
涯！
Gai!
集！
そのヴォイドは…。
Shu?!
That Void...
これを使えって
誰かが僕に言った。
Someone told me to use this.
And you know who, don't you?!
涯は知ってるんだろう！？
Tsugumi, how long before it fires?
鶫。
発射までの時間は？
あと３０秒だよ！
Thirty seconds!
Everybody hear that?
Hold out for thirty seconds!
（鶫）みんな聞こえた！？
３０秒　こらえて！
（大雲）イエス。　ブラックスワン。
（兵士）ぐあっ！
Yes, Black Swan.
（綾瀬）「させない！！」
Oh no you don't!
《僕だけの願いじゃない！》
This isn't my wish alone.
《僕だけの力じゃない！》
This isn't my power alone!
（鶫）今だよ！
Now!
うあああっ！！
♪♪～
"70-year-old finishes marathon!"
（颯太）おっ！
よっしゃあ！
Yes!
♪♪～
Why did you come? One sinner is plenty.
どうして来た？
罪人は　俺だけで十分だ。
言ったろ？　手伝うって。
I said I'd help, didn't I?
これで　僕も共犯だね。
I guess this makes me your accomplice.
（ユウ）
ありがとう。　修一郎。
Thank you, Shuichiro.
Cocytus trembled.
（ユウ）コキュートスが
震えました。→
She should wake up any time now.
彼女は　間もなく
目を覚ますでしょう。
（ユウ）いとしい
彼女の王を求めて…。
Seeking her beloved king...
Keep holding my hand tight and don't let go
♪♪～
Tell me you'll stay with me
Your hand in mine was warm and kind